Ian Fleshman-Cooper

Kirkland, WA 98033 | Phone: (425) 495-3453 | Email: ian.fleshmancooper@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-fleshman-cooper-934995163/

GitHub: https://github.io/Portfolio 2.0/index.html

Summary

Full-stack web developer with a BA and Summa Cum Laude honors in Mathematics and IT from Northwest University. Certificate in Full-stack web development from the University of Washington. Currently an Academic Advisor for Northwest University for the past two years, with valuable experience in solving solutions to create efficiency, consultant for students, and collaborate with/train a team of advisors to reach team goals. Developed a system for updating current software to help with system maintenance and data tracking. Aim is to bring these fundamentals to a much more technical scale. With a drive to learn and proven experience as a reliable team player and supportive leader looking to serve and help others achieve goals through efficiency and simplicity.

Technical Skills

<u>Languages:</u> JavaScript, ES6, JSX, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, React

<u>Applications:</u> jQuery, JSON, Materialize, AJAX, Bootstrap, Node.JS, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Handlebars, Express.JS, API's, Restful API, React Hooks, Heroku, GIT, GitHub, GitBash, Terminal

Projects | Relevant Experience

Game & GIF

https://github.com/Tskading/Game-Meme | https://tskading.github.io/Game-Meme/

Game & GIF is a website that contains a database of video game information along with a variety of GIFs that correlate with the game.

Role: My role was to develop the carousel that holds and displays the GIFs, while also dynamically applying the GIFs to the carousel based on the users' search. I was also responsible for overall project review and had adjusted certain features, such as making our side bar and navigation menu more dynamic specific to the searched game.

<u>Utilized:</u> JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML, RAWG API, GIPHY API, Slack, Zoom

Workday Scheduler

https://github.com/Ianaac27/Work Day Scheduler|https://ianaac27.github.io/Work Day Scheduler/

An application that is meant to keep track of the users' daily agenda within their workday hours. Role: My role was to set the background color of each timeslot to indicate whether the time has passed, if it is the current hour, or whether the time slot has not passed yet. I was also responsible for developing a function to allow the user to save their notes within their local storage.

Utilized: JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML, Moments.JS

Password Generator

https://github.com/Ianaac27/Password_Generator https://ianaac27.github.io/Password_Generator/

This application will generate a random password based on a series of prompts and confirmations for the user.

Role: My role was to develop the main function of the app by applying a chain of functions to generate a randomized, unsolvable password. I was also responsible for creating the "generate" button which generates a new password after receiving data through a series of prompts, while also creating a "reset" button to reset and create a new password.

<u>Utilized:</u> JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Experience

NPP Academic Advisor Northwest University

2018 - Present

Kirkland, WA

Assist students with a plan for their higher education. Consult with students and staff and manage tasks and computer systems. Familiarity with many software applications such as Excel, Access, PowerCampus, Salesforce, Calendly, Microsoft 365, Teams, and Zoom.

• Gained valuable experience in establishing leadership as I was involved in training and managing new team members. I also had the privilege to develop and maintain a system in which was key for data tracking and keeping up with quarterly goals.

Technology Assistant

2017 - 2018

Sultan School District

Sultan, WA

Repair computers, projectors and mimio boards - such as keyboards, screens, hard drive replacements, etc.

Paraprofessional

2014 - 2018

Sultan School District

Sultan, WA

Support children and teens in their learning through encouragement, brainstorming for ideas, social expectations, as well as relationship building. Classroom management, communication with students and their parents, and tutoring and one-on-one support.

• Recognized as employee of the month twice by my colleagues and peers.

Education

Full- Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Washington – Seattle, WA 24-week intensive program gaining technical programming skills in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, React JS, MongoDB, Node.JS as well as going in depth with Algorithms, Efficiency, and Data Structures.

Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics and Information Technology: Northwest University - Kirkland, WA | Summa Cum Laude – Annual Dean's List

Associates Degree: Shoreline Community College - Shoreline, WA

Annual Dean's List